Matthew Lui

mattclui@gmail.com • Irvine, CA • mattclui.github.io • mattlui

PROFILE

I am a full-stack software engineer based in Irvine, California. After working for over a decade in investment management, I decided to invest in myself and pursue my passion for problem solving through programming. Most recently I co-created Snowclone, an open source backend-as-a-service supporting realtime applications.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer and Co-Creator,

Jan 2024 - Apr 2024

Snowclone (snowclone-base.github.io) ∅

Snowclone is an open-source backend-as-a-service that streamlines the process of provisioning and managing cloud infrastructure for the deployment of realtime-enabled web applications.

- Developed a service to launch a Postgres database, a schema-uploading UI, a REST API, and a realtime notifications server with a single command (Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, PostgREST, SSE, Docker)
- Engineered a secure containerized backend infrastructure for cloud deployment (AWS: ECS Fargate, RDS, ALB, Route 53)
- Architected a solution to deploy Snowclone's stack of services to AWS within minutes, abstracting away configuration and provisioning of the 50+ necessary resources (Terraform)
- Built a CLI to facilitate the deployment and removal of backends, condensing dozens of configuration steps into six simple commands (AWS: S3, DynamoDB; Node.js)
- Authored an in-depth technical case study, readable at snowclone-base.github.io/casestudy/introduction/ ∂
- Collaborated with a team of four remote engineers using agile workflow (Slack, Github)

Software Engineer, *Self-Employed*

2022 – 2024 | Irvine, CA

Developed freelance open-source applications including:

- *Rekwestbin* Tool for collecting and inspecting webhooks (DO Droplet, Nginx, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Express, EJS)
- Prayer Partner App for recording and tracking prayer requests (JavaScript, Express, MongoDB)

Vice President, Investment Research, Canterbury Consulting

2018 – 2022 | Newport Beach, CA

- Chaired the global equity research team, overseeing \$10B+ in public equity and alternative investments for individuals, endowments, and foundations
- Managed over 70 relationships with investment firms and negotiated fee savings of \$1,400,000 on behalf of clients

SKILLS

Backend	Frontend	Cloud	Other
Node.js, Express, Go,	JavaScript, React,	DigitalOcean, AWS,	Git/Github, Docker,
PostgreSQL,	Handlebars,	Terraform, Render	HTTP, WebSockets,
MongoDB, REST APIs	HTML/CSS		Jest, OOP, Nginx,
			Postman

EDUCATION

Launch School. 2022 – 2024

Software Engineering and Full-Stack Development &

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum

University of California, Berkeley, Bachelor of Arts, Economics